<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SEBOL</title>
    <description>Sociedad de Economistas de Bolivia</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title> Research highlight</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;promoting-renewable-energy-and-the-risk-of-energy-poverty-in-chile&quot;&gt;Promoting renewable energy and the risk of energy poverty in Chile&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luis Gonzales (SEBOL, University of Chicago)&lt;/strong&gt; contributed the following investigation: &lt;strong&gt;Promoting renewable energy and the risk of energy poverty in Chile&lt;/strong&gt; as a chapter to the book: &lt;em&gt;“Narratives of Low-Carbon Transitions: Understanding Risks and Uncertainties. Edited by: Susanne Hanger-Kopp and Jenny Lieu, Alexandros Nikas. Routledge, London. 2019”&lt;/em&gt;. The chapter is co-authored with Rodrigo Cerda (CLAPES-UC). Congratulations  Luis!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is part of the &lt;strong&gt;Transitions Pathways and Risk Analysis for Climate Change Mitigation and Adaptation Strategies - TransRisk&lt;/strong&gt;, started in September 2015 under the umbrella of EU Horizon 2020 programme.The volume provides an interdisciplinary, conceptual framework to assess risks and uncertainties associated with low-carbon policies and applies this consistently across 11 country cases from around the world, illustrating alternative transition pathways in various contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;paper-summary&quot;&gt;Paper summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past decade Chile has successfully followed a low-carbon pathway based largely on solar power and has received international praise for this positive development. However, on closer analysis this trajectory may have a negative impact by amplifying energy poverty. The Chilean narrative discusses the country’s low-carbon pathway in the context of other objectives. It focuses particularly on the carbon tax established in 2017 as a manifestation of the country’s commitment to this pathway, and the potential risk of increasing energy poverty under four scenarios. This risk could be mitigated by creating a mechanism for monetary compensation for the most vulnerable population. The engagement process designed for this analysis revealed additional risks and uncertainties associated with Chile’s low-carbon futures that cannot (yet) be quantified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the book for free here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429458781&quot;&gt;https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429458781&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![image-title-here](/img/posts/johanna.png){:class=&quot;img-responsive&quot;} --&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;bibtex&quot;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
@incollection{GonzalesCerda2019,
  author       = {Gonzales, Luis, and Cerda, Ricardo},
  title        = {Promoting renewable energy and the risk of energy poverty in Chile},
  booktitle    = {Narratives of Low-Carbon Transitions: Understanding Risks and Uncertainties},
  chapter      = 6,
  publisher    = {Routledge},
  year         = 2019,
  address      = {London},
  editor       = {Hanger-Kopp, Susanne and Lieu, Jenny},
  edition      = 1,
  month        = 2,
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/12/reshighlight-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/12/reshighlight-1/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> BCDE10 Announcement</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-10th-bcde-to-be-hosted-by-upb---la-paz&quot;&gt;The 10th BCDE to be hosted by UPB - La Paz&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to announce that the 10th Bolivian Conference on Development Economics (BCDE10) will take place in La Paz, Bolivia, on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday November 14 and Friday November 15, 2019&lt;/strong&gt;. The conference this year is jointly organized by the &lt;strong&gt;Bolivian Society of Economists (SEBOL)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Universidad Privada Boliviana (UPB)&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Institute for Advanced Development Studies (INESAD)&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;Bolivian Academy of Economic Sciences (ABCE)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working on the logistics and contacting outstanding speakers, we hope you can join us in La Paz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;keynote-speaker&quot;&gt;Keynote Speaker&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johanna Rickne&lt;/strong&gt;  is Associate Professor in Economics at the Swedish Institute for Social Research, Stockholm University, and an affiliated researcher at the Uppsala Center for Labor Studies (Uppsala University), the Stockholm China Economic Research Center (Stockholm School of Economics), and the Research Institute for Industrial Economics. During the 2018/2019 academic year, she is Guest Professor of Economics at Yale University (Cowles Foundation). Her research is focused on labor economics, political economics, and gender economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;special-guests&quot;&gt;Special Guests&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marcelo Olarreaga&lt;/strong&gt; is Professor of Economics at the University of Geneva, and Research Fellow at the Centre for Economic Policy Research (CEPR) in London. His research is focused on trade, economic growth and political economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Miguel Benavente&lt;/strong&gt;  is head of the Competitiveness and Innovation Division of the Inter-American Development Bank. His research is focused on innovation, entrepreneurship, economic development, and SME financing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-information&quot;&gt;Important Information&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!-- * **Attendance**: we're expecting over 200 attendees. --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference Date&lt;/strong&gt;: November 14-15, 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call for papers and sessions&lt;/strong&gt;: TBA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/johanna.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-title-here&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details about speakers, BCDE10, and logistics will appear in the conference website:&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sebol.org/bcde10&quot;&gt;www.sebol.org/bcde10/&lt;/a&gt;, in the meantime like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Sociedad-de-Economistas-de-Bolivia-379788332035459/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, follow on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=SEBOLBolivia&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or subcribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://mc.us15.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=32ecc95787a5980a33901b562&amp;amp;id=cc247ac02b&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bcde8.org/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; in order not to miss any important updates about the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/noticias/bcde10</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/noticias/bcde10</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reunion de mitad de año</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;reunión-de-mitad-de-año-2019&quot;&gt;Reunión de mitad de año 2019&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nos complace anunciar que a partir de 2019 vamos a tener una reunión de mitad de año en Washington D.C. Esta reunión tiene dos objetivos:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Crear un espacio adicional para investigadores jóvenes, incluyendo los miembros de SEBOL, donde podamos discutir ideas nuevas en temas relacionados al desarrollo.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Esperamos que esta reunión se convierta en una incubadora de talento que ayude al desarrollo profesional de investigadores jóvenes ofreciéndoles la oportunidad de interactuar de cerca con académicos establecidos.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esta reunión complementa el esfuerzo que realizamos todos los años con nuestro congreso anual—conocido como BCDE por su sigla en inglés. Por una parte, esta reunión dará una oportunidad a investigadores que desearían participar del BCDE pero que encuentran difícil viajar a Bolivia todos los años. Por otra parte, aquellos investigadores que pueden asistir a ambas reuniones, tienen libertad de presentar en el BCDE de noviembre una versión corregida del proyecto presentado en el taller de julio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;formato&quot;&gt;Formato&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La reunión tendrá el formato de un taller académico de un día a realizarse el &lt;strong&gt;26 de julio de 2019&lt;/strong&gt;. Esperamos discutir de 6 a 8 documentos de investigación. Después de la presentación, cada documento será discutido primero por un comentarista y luego en plenaria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;invitados&quot;&gt;Invitados&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ya tenemos confirmada la participación de investigadores con reconocimiento internacional. En particular, nos da mucho gusto anunciar que &lt;strong&gt;Miguel Urquiola, de Columbia University&lt;/strong&gt;, ofrecerá la &lt;strong&gt;charla principal&lt;/strong&gt; de esta reunión inaugural. Los comentaristas confirmados incluyen Pamela Jakiela (Center for Global Development), Miguel Zarzosa (Purdue University), Owen Ozier (World Bank).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;presentación-de-propuestas&quot;&gt;Presentación de propuestas&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Los interesados en participar pueden enviar resumenes extendidos (extended abstracts) o borradores de documentos hasta el &lt;strong&gt;13 de mayo de 2019&lt;/strong&gt; via correo electrónico al organizador principal, &lt;strong&gt;Walter Valdivia&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:wvaldivi@gmu.edu&quot;&gt;wvaldivi@gmu.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las propuestas serán evaluadas por un comité formado por miembros de SEBOL y en consulta con los comentaristas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;más-información&quot;&gt;Más información&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mayor información está disponible en el sitio web del taller: &lt;a href=&quot;/dsw/&quot;&gt; www.sebol.org/dsw/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La versión electrónica (pdf) de la invitación está disponible &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/DSW_CallforPapers_Final.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;acá.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- More details about speakers, BCDE9, and logistics will appear in subsequent posts, in the meantime like us on [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/Sociedad-de-Economistas-de-Bolivia-379788332035459/), follow on [Twitter](https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=SEBOLBolivia), or subcribe to our [mailing list](https://mc.us15.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=32ecc95787a5980a33901b562&amp;amp;id=cc247ac02b) and [RSS feed](http://www.bcde8.org/feed.xml) in order not to miss any important updates about the conference. --&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/dsw-call/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/01/dsw-call/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title> BCDE9 Announcement</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-9th-bcde-to-be-hosted-by-upsa&quot;&gt;The 9th BCDE to be hosted by UPSA&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re very excited to announce that the 9th Bolivian Conference on Development Economics (BCDE9) will be hosted by &lt;strong&gt;Universidad Privada de Santa Cruz (UPSA)&lt;/strong&gt;, on November 29-30, 2018. The conference is jointly organized by the &lt;strong&gt;Sociedad de Economistas de Bolivia (SEBOL)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Instituto de Estudios Avanzados para el Desarrollo (INESAD)&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Academia Boliviana de Ciencias Económicas (ABCE)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working on the logistics and contacting outstanding speakers, we hope you can join us in Santa Cruz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;keynote-speaker&quot;&gt;Keynote Speaker&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ariel Kalil (Ph.D. University of Michigan)&lt;/strong&gt; is a professor at the University of Chicago-Harris School of Public Policy. At Harris, she directs the Center for Human Potential and Public Policy and co-directs the Behavioral Insights and Parenting Lab. Ariel is a developmental psychologist who studies economic conditions, parenting, and child development. Her current research examines the historical evolution of income-based gaps in parenting behavior and children’s cognitive and non-cognitive skills. She is leading a variety of field experiments designed to strengthen parental engagement and child development in low-income families using tools drawn from behavioral economics and neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-information&quot;&gt;Important Information&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;!-- * **Attendance**: we're expecting over 200 attendees. --&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: 29-30 of November.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call for papers and sessions&lt;/strong&gt;: TBA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/Kalil9BCDE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-title-here&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details about speakers, BCDE9, and logistics will appear in subsequent posts, in the meantime like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Sociedad-de-Economistas-de-Bolivia-379788332035459/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, follow on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=SEBOLBolivia&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, or subcribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://mc.us15.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=32ecc95787a5980a33901b562&amp;amp;id=cc247ac02b&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bcde8.org/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; in order not to miss any important updates about the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2018 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/16/bcde9-announcement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/03/16/bcde9-announcement/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nueva Página de SEBOL</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;bienvenidos&quot;&gt;Bienvenidos&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hemos rediseñado nuestra página web para ofrecer un contenido más dinámico y actualizado a nuestros usuarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gracias por visitarnos y ayudanos a compartir esta información a través de:
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Sociedad-de-Economistas-de-Bolivia-379788332035459/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; y &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=SEBOLBolivia&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/03/15/hello/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/03/15/hello/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Convocatoria para documentos de trabajo</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Estamos encantados de anunciar que la 8va Conferencia en Desarrollo Económico (BCDE8) se llevará a cabo en Cochabamba, Bolivia el jueves 26 y viernes 27 de octubre de 2017. La conferencia es organizada por el Instituto de Estudios Avanzados para el Desarrollo (INESAD), la Sociedad de Economistas de Bolivia (SEBOL), la Universidad Privada Boliviana (UPB) y la Academia Boliviana de Ciencias Económicas (ABCE).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La conferencia reunirá a académicos nacionales e internacionales para intercambiar y discutir avances recientes en la investigación teórica y aplicada en temas de desarrollo económico. En particular invitamos a jóvenes investigadores y a mujeres investigadoras  a enviar documentos de investigación en todos los temas relacionados al campo del desarrollo económico.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Este año tenemos el agrado de contar con dos disertaciones magistrales a cargo de Sara Farley (Global Knowledge Initiative) y Carlos Végh (Banco Mundial).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lugar&quot;&gt;Lugar&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La BCDE8 se llevará a cabo en el campus de la Universidad Privada Boliviana (UPB) en Cochabamba, Bolivia. Mayor información sobre la ciudad y detalles de logística están disponibles &lt;a href=&quot;/logistics&quot;&gt;acá&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;expositores-principales&quot;&gt;Expositores Principales&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sara Farley (M.Sc. Stanford University) es directora ejecutiva de operaciones (Chief Operating Officer) y cofundadora de la Iniciativa de Conocimiento Global (GKI), una organización que sirve a más de 60 países. Ha sido distinguida por la Fundación Rockefeller como una de los “100 Mejores Innovadores Sociales del Próximo Siglo”. Las actividades de GKI incluyen entrenamiento en innovación colaborativa, optimización de programas de redes y estrategias de cooperación colaborativa junto a otras instituciones que como el Banco Mundial, Comunidad del Este del África, Banco de Desarrollo Africano, entre otras.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Carlos Végh (Ph.D. University of Chicago) es el economista jefe del Banco Mundial para América Latina y el Caribe. Antes de asumir este cargo, Végh fue el profesor Fred H. Sanderson de Economía Internacional en la Escuela de Estudios Internacionales Avanzados (SAIS) de la Universidad John Hopkins e investigador asociado en la Oficina Nacional de Investigación Económica (NBER). También se desempeñó como profesor de economía en la Universidad de California, Los Ángeles (UCLA) y como profesor de economía en la Universidad de Maryland. Tiene numerosas publicaciones en revistas académicas especializadas en temas de política monetaria y fiscal en países emergentes y en desarrollo. Es coeditor de un volumen en honor a Guillermo Calvo (MIT Press) y ha publicado un libro de texto de nivel doctoral sobre macroeconomía de economías abiertas en países en desarrollo (MIT Press). Adicionalmente ha sido consultor para el Fondo Monetario Internacional (FMI), Banco Mundial, Banco Interamericano de Desarrollo (BID) y varios Bancos Centrales del mundo.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;sobre-la-conferencia&quot;&gt;Sobre la conferencia&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;La BCDE8 es la continuación de otras conferencias organizadas en las ciudades de La Paz, Cochabamba y Santa Cruz que atrajeron académicos e investigadores de alto nivel, entre los que se incluye como principales oradores a Norman Loayza (Banco Mundial), Miguel Urquiola (Columbia), Beatriz Armendáriz (Harvard), Máximo Torero (IFPRI), Santiago Levy (BID), James Robinson (Chicago), Rodrigo Soares (Columbia), Eduardo Lora (Harvard Kennedy School of Government), Roberto Rigobon (MIT), Eduardo Engel (Yale), David Bishai (Johns Hopkins), y Francisco H. G. Ferreira (Banco Mundial).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;viaje-y-estadía&quot;&gt;Viaje y estadía&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todos los participantes deben cubrir sus propios gastos de viajes y estadía. Sin embargo, los organizadores negociarán tasas preferenciales en varios hoteles de Cochabamba durante los días de la conferencia. Para más información visita: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bcde8.org/logistics&quot;&gt;www.bcde8.org/logistics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becas de ayuda de hasta 700 dólares americanos se ofrecerán para algunos de los participantes que viven fuera de Bolivia y cuyos documentos de investigación hayan sido aceptados en base a criterios de calidad académica. Los interesados en ser considerados para estos fondos deberán enviar un correo electrónico a &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rnogales@sebol.org&quot;&gt;rnogales@sebol.org&lt;/a&gt; luego de enviar sus documentos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;documentos-de-investigación&quot;&gt;Documentos de investigación&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fecha límite:&lt;/strong&gt; viernes 11 de agosto de 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recepción de documentos:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2r6pkd0&quot;&gt;http://bit.ly/2r6pkd0&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Todos los documentos recibidos serán revisados por un comité antes ser aceptados en la conferencia. El proceso de revisión terminará hasta el viernes 1ro de septiembre y los organizadores comunicaran los resultados del proceso de selección vía correo electrónico. El programa detallado estará disponible en el sitio web de la conferencia posteriormente.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;consultas&quot;&gt;Consultas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En caso de consultas sobre el envío de documentos y el programa, por favor contactar a los organizadores a la siguiente dirección: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rnogales@sebol.org&quot;&gt;rnogales@sebol.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/23/call-for-papers-es/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/06/23/call-for-papers-es/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for Papers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to announce that the 8th Bolivian Conference on Development Economics (BCDE8) will take place in Cochabamba, Bolivia, on Thursday October 26 and Friday October 27, 2017. The conference this year is jointly organized by the Institute for Advanced Development Studies (INESAD), the Society of Bolivian Economists (SEBOL), Universidad Privada Boliviana (UPB), and the Bolivian Academy of Economic Science (ABCE).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference brings together local and international scholars for the exchange of ideas and discussion of recent results within theoretical and applied development economics research. We particularly encourage female researchers and Bolivian researchers to submit papers on all topics within the field of development economics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCDE8 keynote speakers will be Sara Farley (Global Knowledge Initiative) and Carlos Végh (World Bank).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;venue&quot;&gt;Venue&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BCDE8 will take place in the city of Cochabamba, Bolivia, at the main campus of Universidad Privada Boliviana (UPB).
Information about the city and logistics is available &lt;a href=&quot;/logistics&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;keynote-speakers&quot;&gt;Keynote Speakers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sara Farley (M.Sc. Stanford University) is Chief Operating Officer and Co-Founder of the Global Knowledge Initiative (GKI), an organization serving more than 60 countries and one that The Rockefeller Foundation designated as one of the “Top 100 Social Innovations for the next century”. Current GKI activities include collaborative innovation training, network optimization programs, and collaborative innovation strategy setting with partners including the World Bank, East African Community, African Development Bank, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Carlos Végh (Ph.D. University of Chicago) is the World Bank Chief Economist for Latin America and the Caribbean. Prior to starting his job at the World Bank, he was the Fred H. Sanderson Professor of International Economics at the Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies (SAIS) and a Research Associate at the National Bureau of Economic Research (NBER). He also served as Professor of Economics and Vice-Chair of Undergraduate Studies at UCLA, and before that as Chair of the Program in Comparative and Topical Studies at UCLA’s Latin American Center. He has published extensively in leading academic journals on monetary and fiscal policy in developing and emerging countries. He has co-edited a volume in honor of Guillermo Calvo (MIT Press) and  published a graduate textbook on open economy macroeconomics for developing countries (MIT Press). He has been a consultant for the IMF, World Bank, IDB, and many Central Banks around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;invited-guest-speakers&quot;&gt;Invited Guest Speakers:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Andrés Fernández (Ph.D. Rutgers University) is a Research Economist in the Research Department at the Inter-American Development Bank. His main research agenda focuses on building, calibrating and estimating dynamic stochastic general equilibrium models for emerging economies to  study the sources of business cycles in emerging economies.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Juan Vargas (Ph.D. University of London) is a Research Economist at CAF-Development Bank of Latin America. Juan held various academic and scholar positions in the U.S., Europe and Latin America. His research focuses on the political economy of conflict and the economic determinants of crime and violence.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-to-expect&quot;&gt;What to expect?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCDE8 follows up on the success of previous conferences held in La Paz, Cochabamba, and Santa Cruz, that attracted prestigious researchers and policymakers, and included keynote lectures by Norman Loayza (World Bank), Miguel Urquiola (Columbia), Beatriz Armendáriz (Harvard), Máximo Torero (IFPRI), Santiago Levy (IADB), James Robinson (Chicago), Rodrigo Soares (Columbia), Eduardo Lora (Harvard Kennedy School of Government), Roberto Rigobon (MIT), Eduardo Engel (Yale), David Bishai (Johns Hopkins), and Francisco H. G. Ferreira (World Bank).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;travel-and-accommodation&quot;&gt;Travel and accommodation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All participants must cover their own travel and accommodation costs, but the organizers have arranged for preferential rates at hotels in Cochabamba. For details check: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bcde8.org/logistics&quot;&gt;www.bcde8.org/logistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A travel stipend of up to 700 USD will be offered to some of the successful applicants residing outside Bolivia, based on the quality of their submissions. Applicants interested in being considered for one of these stipends, should send an email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rnogales@sebol.org&quot;&gt;rnogales@sebol.org&lt;/a&gt; after submitting their papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;paper-submissions&quot;&gt;Paper submissions&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline:&lt;/strong&gt; is Friday August 11, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please submit your papers&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2r6pkd0&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All submitted papers will be reviewed prior to acceptance for presentation. The review process will finish by Friday September 1, 2017, and the organizers will notify applicants of the outcome by email. A program with details of all scheduled presentations will be posted at the Conference’s web site. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;Contact&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to contact the organizers by e-mail at: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rnogales@sebol.org&quot;&gt;rnogales@sebol.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 05:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/09/call-for-papers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/09/call-for-papers/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
